A Guide to the Papers of Mason C. Andrews 1932-1997
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- E.V.M.S.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Medical center talks (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "A new medical school in Norfolk" pamphlets (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Eastern Virginia Medical School 1973-1974 bulletin (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Eastern Virginia Medical School Robert T. Manning, M.D. (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Eastern Virginia Medical School yearbook 1976 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Transportation planning 1977 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 10)
    - The Kling partnership (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Eastern Virginia Medical School-facilities program, March 12, 1974-Vincent G. Kling and Partners, Architects March 12, 1974 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Faculty recruitment progam: Eastern Virginia Medical School (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Chairman, Department of Surgery (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Report of the survey E.V.M.S. by the Liaison Committee on medical education of the AMA and AAMC (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 3)
    - E.V.M.S. site visit (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Present status of facilities development at Eastern Virginia Medical School (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Master plan update for the Eastern Virginia Medical Center January 1979 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Eastern Virginia Medical Center: master plan June 1981 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1992, 1995, 2000 master plans-Norfolk Medical Center 1992, 1995, 2000 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Financial Statements 1988 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 9)
    - E.V.M.S. financial plan for first ten years of operation (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum
    - Elective opportunities booklet 1971-1972 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Curriculum: Eastern Virginia Medical School (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Proposal-behavioral science program in medical education (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Curriculum development for the Eastern Virginia Medical School (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Medical School Education" Journal of Medical Education 1970 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Jones Institute
    - Jones Institute-draft copy Serono/EVMA agreement July 1984 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Meetings of the Royal College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Report of the committee of inquiry into human fertilization and embryology July 1984 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Reports (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 6)
- Community Services
  - Miscellaneous
    - City Planning Commission 1961-1962 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 7)
    - City Planning Commission 1963-1964 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 8)
    - City Planning Commission Brochures (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Health-Welfare-Recreation Planning Council (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk Chamber of Commerce (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Rotary Club (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Tidewater Regional Health Planning Council 1971 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 4)
    - United Community Funds and Councils of America (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Fetal/Infant Mortality Review Program-Community Review Board (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Awards
    - Nominating Letters for AMA's Benjamin Rush Award (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Norfolk First Citizen: Congratulatory Letters (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Cosmopolitan Club of Norfolk: Norfolk's First Citizen 1967 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors
    - C + P Telephone - Director's Reference Binder I (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 11)
    - C + P Telephone - Director's Reference Binder II (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 12)
    - C + P Telephone - Annual Review 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 13)
    - C + P Telephone: Energy conservation trailer (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 14)
    - C + P Telephone: Security briefing information (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 1)
    - C + P Telephone: Correspondence (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 2)
    - C + P Telephone: Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 3)
    - First VA Bank: Board of Directors (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors: Recreation Planning Council 1967 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Southern Bank of Norfolk (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Tidewater Westminster Homes (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Good Music Corp. and WRVC-FM (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Sabine Andrews
    - Junior League of Norfolk (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Kids (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Planning Council (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Red Cross-Voluntary Advisory Board (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Urban Coalition (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 13)
- Norfolk City Government
  - City Council Papers
    - Miscellaneous Papers 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Papers 1976 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Papers 1977-1982 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Papers 1988 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Papers 1989 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Papers 1990-1991 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Papers 1992 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Papers July-October 1994 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Papers November 1-7 1994 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Papers November 8-16 1994 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Papers June-September 1995 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Papers October 1995 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Papers 1997 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 13)
    - At-Large Voting System (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Campaign 1996 1996 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Campaign Brochures (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Campaign Regulations (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Captital Improvment Program FY 1998-2002 1998-2002 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Captital Improvement Program 1964-1968 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 6)
    - City Planning Commission (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 7)
    - City Rebirth (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Collective Bargaining (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Community Development Block Grant (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Consultants (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence Re: Virginian Pilot article "City buys up downtown out of necessity and hope" (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Cox Cable (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Chrysler Museum (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Cultural Resurgence (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Downtown Development 1961-1979 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Downtown Development 1994-1997 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Downtown Graphics (Directional signs) (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Downtown Moving Message Sign (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Downtown Norfolk Campus of TCC-Preliminary Design 1993 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Empowerment Zone application (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Empowerment Zone Correspondence (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Environmental Quality (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Finance and bond rating (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Ghent Rehabilitation (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Greater Norfolk Corporation (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Harrison Opera House (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Location and Design Study-Waterfront Drive 1963 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "New Norfolk" September 1967 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Norfolk Redevelopment and housing authority (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Norfolk Regional Slides (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 4)
    - The Norfolk Story 1966, 1973 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Norfolk Works, Inc. (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Old Dominion University (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Parking, Downtown 1997 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 8)
    - PACE-Cadet Program (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Popular election of mayor (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Port of Hampton Roads (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Preserving Norfolk's Heritage: Proposed zoning for historic and cultural conservation (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Real Estate assessment 1974 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Refinery (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Revenue Sharing (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Taxes (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Urban Development Action Grant (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Urban Land Institute (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Various Partnerships/Projects (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Waterfront-brochures (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Water and Sewer Changes (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Water supply system (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Transportation
    - Hampton Roads Crossing Study (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Transportation Task Force (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Light Rail (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Hurricane Evacuation Interstate Highway Plan 1995 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Cousteau Ocean Center
    - Economic projections, feasibility studies (Box-folder Box 24, folder 1)
    - Lease Agreement (Box-folder Box 24, folder 2)
    - Legal papers (Box-folder Box 24, folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 24, folder 4)
  - Nauticus
    - National Maritime Center Authority (Nauticus) 1995 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Report-Summary of correspondence concerning the National Martitime Center Authority and the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 1986-1993 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Captital campaign (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Marketing Plans (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Hampton Roads Naval Museum (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Waterside
    - Development of Waterside Festival Marketplace (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Revenue Reports (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Rouse &Co. (Architect) (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Brochures (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Mac Arthur Center
    - Design Plans (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Land Disposition and Development Contract (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence 1993-1995 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Financing (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Articles, press releases, brochures (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Park Place
    - Park Place Steering Committee (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Park Place Redevelopment Foundation Bylaws (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Park Place Community Development Corporation meeting materials 1993 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Park Place Community Development Corporation meeting materials 1994 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Park Place Community Development Corporation correspondence 1993-1995 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Economic Empowerment Demonstration Project (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Rouse &Co. (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 7)
    - General correspondence 1992-1995 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Commissions and Task Forces
    - Norfolk Public Housing Task Force (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk Public Housing Task Force Workbook (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Hampton Roads Planning District Commission 1994-1995 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Southeastern Virginia Planning District Commission Regional Housing Strategic Plan 1989 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Southeastern Virginia Planning District Commission 1989 Economic Outlook 1989 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Southeastern Virginia Planning District Commission Southeastern Transportation Control Plan 1984 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Southeastern Virginia Planning District Commission "Evaluation of transportation control strategies for Southeastern Virginia" 1983 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Southeastern Virginia Planning District Commission correspondence 1989 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Southeastern Virginia Planning District Commission-Suggested draft of the comprehensive plan 1964 (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Task Force on Violence and Crime Reduction 1992 (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Report to the Task Force on Violence and Crime Reduction 1992 (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Vision for Parks, Boulevards, and Waterways Steering/Oversight Committee (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Speeches
    - Civic Luncheon Speech (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Community Development (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence Re: Speeches (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Health Care Reform (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Honoring Individuals (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Law Enforcement (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Military (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Openings/Dedications (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Talks to visiting groups and conventions (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Mayor's Files
    - Correspondence (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Azalea Festival Mayor's Schedule 1994 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Letters of congratulations on election as Mayor (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Mayor's Institute on City Design 1993 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 7)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - Architects (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Busing 1982 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Busing January-March 1983 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Busing April-May 1983 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Busing June-November 1983 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Busing 1984-1985 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Busing 1986 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 7)
  - City Council Campaign 1996 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 8)
  - City Goverment (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Church Street 1976-1978 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Colley Avenue Bridge (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Cousteau Center (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Downtown 1960-1978 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Downtown 1979-1980 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Downtown 1981-1982 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Downtown 1983 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Downtown 1984-1985 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Election as Mayor (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Ghent 1976-1978 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Hampton Blvd. 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 6)
  - In-Vitro Fertilization 1978-1979 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 7)
  - In-Vitro Fertilization 1980-1981 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 8)
  - In-Vitro Fertilization 1982 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 9)
  - In-Vitro Fertilization 1983-1992 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Kaufman, Charles L. (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 2)
  - NAMCA (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Medical Center (not dated) (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Medical Center 1961-1966 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Medical Center 1967-1970 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Medical Center 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Medical Tower (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Topics (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Ocean View 1976-1986 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Old Bay Line (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Planning Commission 1960-1962 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Planning Commission 1963 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Planning Commission 1964-1965 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Planning Commission 1967-1969 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Public Administration (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Roads (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Stadium 1976-1995 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Rouse &Co. (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Urban Redevelopment (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Waterside April 1981-May 1983 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Waterside June 1983-June 1995 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 11)
- Binders &Published Materials
  - City Goverment
    - Approved Operating Budget-City of Norfolk July 1997-June 1998 (Box Box 34)
    - Breaking down the glass wall: A proposal for the Norfolk Empowerment Zone (Box Box 34)
    - Comparative Report of Local Goverment Revenues and Expenditures-Year ended June 30, 1990 June 30, 1990 (Box Box 34)
    - Congestion Management System for Hampton Roads, VA 1995 (Box Box 34)
    - Downtown Norfolk-Briefing book for the Urban Land Institute Panel 1989 (Box Box 34)
    - General Plan of Norfolk 1992 (Box Box 35)
    - Hampton Roads Crossing Study-Draft purpose and need statment and technical appendix 1994 (Box Box 35)
    - "A Larger Vision..." Jim Rouse and the American City 1994 (Box Box 35)
    - Mayors Institute on City Design 1993 (Box Box 35)
    - Police Annual Report 1992 (Box Box 36)
    - Priority: Home! The federal plan to break the cycle of homelessness 1994 (Box Box 36)
    - Survey and Analysis of the Norfolk Chamber of Commerce 1966 (Box Box 36)
    - The Virginia Waterfront-Regional Travel and Tourism Study Economic Impact Analysis 1994 (Box Box 36)
    - The Virginia Waterfront-Regional Travel and Tourism Study Post Advertising Survey 1994 (Box Box 36)
    - Working Master Plan for the Partnerships for Excellence Capital Campaign 1988 (Box Box 36)
    - Appointment Books (Box Box 36)
  - Medical
    - Photograph binder ca 1910 (Box Box 37)
    - Financial Managment of the Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine 1972 (Box Box 37)
    - Introduction to Endocrinology-a programmed instruction course 1966 (Box Box 37)
    - From a binder: Virginia Obstetrical and Gynecological Society 1948-1965, 3 folders (Box-folder Box 37, Folders 1-3)
- Oversized, Photographs, and Miscellaneous Items
  - Miscellaneous
    - Virginia Obstetrical and Gynecological Society Seal (Box Box 38)
    - Virginia Waterfront Rock Fish Tee-Shirt (Box Box 38)
    - Nauticus-The National Maritime Center 1995 (Box Box 38)
  - Photographs
    - Mason &Family (ca.1950's-1990's) 1950's-1990's (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Medical Center 1962-1967 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Medical Center Aerial Photos 1966-1970 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 3)
    - EVMS (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Waterside (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Victory Party Photographs 1996 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 6)